ROBERT WEISE JR

bobweisejr@gmail.com 6932 Georgetown Ave, Hudsonville MI 49426 231-736-0175

SUMMARY

20+ years of experience in the grocery retail business, including extensive experience in all departments and functions, with over 18 years in managerial roles. Significantly reduced employee turnover and increased productivity by cultivating a fun, rewarding store culture. Multiple records in sales, gross profits, net income, and EBITDA.

Implemented multiple programs utilizing technology to make business operations more efficient, including writing various macros, VBA UserForms and scripts in order to effectively automate complex tasks and establish links between various information technologies and databases. Experienced with nearly every aspect of Smart Grocer: dynamic item reporting, label program, bucket sales, item movement, receiving, cost adjustments, file imports, item management, and more. Since joining Spartan written many SQL algorithms and .bat scripts to better automate systems and reduce errors. Very motivated and interested in teaching myself C# and other programming languages.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Leadership
- Excellent communication
- Analytical thinking
- Even temperament (EI)

- Decision making
- Interpersonal relations and awareness
- Empowers others
- Focused and Driven

EDUCATION

GRAND VALLEY STATE UNIVERSITY

Spring 2012 -Bachelors in Business Administration Majoring in Marketing

Muskegon Community College

2002 - Associates in Business Management

EXPERIENCE

SpartanNash | 850 76th St SW, Byron Center MI 49315

Programmer Analyst II March 2019 - Present

- Electronic Payment Systems (EPS) support and contactless testing
- Fuel Code Administration assisted by implementing a Python program/script to parse .xlsx, .ods, and .pdf files to a consistent universal template for import
- EPS on call and administration- Unix and Linux experience

SpartanNash | 850 76th St SW, Byron Center MI 49315 Retail Systems Analyst II October 2016 – March 2019

- Responsible for Retail Applications support. Smart Grocer, BRdata, CT2020, HHConfig
- Department Expert in Invatron Applications. PlumHost, Eplum, Periscope, Fresh Trax
- Responsible for maintaining applications, detecting, tracing, and communicating software problems. Fixing problems in some situations.

Spring Lake Orchard Market | 17026 Lloyds Bayou Dr, Spring Lake MI 49456 Store Director April 2006 – October 2016

- Responsible for and constantly looking for ways to improve upon store conditions, sales, gross profits, shrink, labor, payroll, expenses, budgets, event planning, employee evaluations, and customer service
- Focus on planning, directing, motivating, and empowering staff to reach financial and customer service goals
- Sustained growth of gross profits, sales, net income, and EBITDA, resulting multiple store records
- Reduced turnover
- Implemented multiple programs resulting in increased efficiency, productivity, and cost savings
- Fostered excellent relationships between store and all vendors, merchants, customers, and staff

Spring Lake Orchard Market | 17026 Lloyds Bayou Dr, Spring Lake MI 49456

Assistant Store Director September 2004 – April 2006

- Assisting Store Director with store conditions, sales, gross profits, shrink, labor, payroll, expenses, budgets, event planning, employee evaluations, and customer service
- Focus in overseeing perishable departments and Front End operations.